Guide to the Dance Program Performance Films, 1990-2012 UA.25.16.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dance Program Performance films
1990-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Dance Program
UA.25.16.0001
2 Linear Feet
The Dance Program Performance Films are a video record of the performances put on by the Duke Dance Program from 1990-2012.
Collection Overview
The Dance Program Performance Films were recorded across three different formats: VHS cassettes, mini-DV cassettes, and DVDs. Most of the Dance Program's performances from 1990-2012 are represented. Recurring dance performances include Choreolab performances, November and December dances, Composition Class final examinations, and Ark dances.
Historical note
In the 1970's, dance at Duke, under the excellent guidance of Julia Wray, was housed in a very supportive Physical Education department. The course offerings included two levels of modern dance technique, modern dance repertory, composition, improvisation, and two or three courses in dance history. Two full length concerts as well as 2 or 3 informal events were offered each year. In the late 70's, two levels of ballet technique were added to the curriculum. In the 80's, after dance was moved from Physical Education and placed within the Institute of the Arts, the program developed increased rigor in its training both in the studio and in theory courses. As the number of full time faculty grew from two to seven, the selection of courses increased dramatically.
Adapted from: http://danceprogram.duke.edu/about/history
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Dance Program Performance Films were received by the University Archives as a transfer in May, 2013.
Dance -- Education; Dance -- Performance; Duke University. Dance Program
- Digital Video Disks, 2005-2012; 1
  - ChoreoLab 2012, 2012 April 21-22; 1
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0016)
  - November Dances 2011, 2011 November 11-12; 2
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0015)
  - ChoreoLab 2011, 2011 April 22-23; 3
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0014)
  - November Dances 2010, 2010 November 20-21; 4
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0013)
  - ChoreoLab 2010, 2010 April 10; 5
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0012)
  - Across the Threshold 2010 2 of 2, 6
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0011)
  - Across the Threshold 2010 1 of 2, 7
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0010)
  - November Dances 2009, 2009 November 21-22; 8
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0009)
  - ChoreoLab 2009, 9
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0008)
  - November Dances 2008, 2008 November; 10
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0007)
  - ChoreoLab 2008, 11
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0006)
  - November Dances 2007, 2007 November 17-18; 12
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0005)
  - ChoreoLab 2007, 2007 April 21-22; 13
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0004)
  - ChoreoLab 2006, 14
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0003)
  - November Dances 2006, 2006 November 18-19; 15
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0002)
  - November Dances 2005, 2005 November 19-20; 16
    - Original optical media (Box 2, Video-disc DVD_0001)
- Digital Video Cassettes, 2001-2008; 2
  - November Dances 2008 Camera 1 Tape 2 Saturday, 2008 November; 17
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0045)
  - November Dances 2008 Camera 2 Tape 1 Sunday, 2008 November; 18
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0044)
  - Orisha Traditions Through Rhythm And Song, 2008 February 23; 19
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0043)
  - ChoreoLab 2008 (Tape 2 of 2), 2008 April 20; 20
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0042)
  - ChoreoLab 2008 (Tape 1 of 2), 2008 April 20; 21
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0041)
  - Across the Threshold 2008 Tape 2, 2008 February 23; 22
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0040)
  - Across the Threshold 2008 Tape 1, 2008 February 23; 23
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0039)
  - November Dances Part II, 2007 November 18; 24
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0038)
  - November Dances Sunday Part I, 2007 November 18; 25
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0037)
  - November Dances Part 3 of 3, 2007 November 18; 26
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0036)
  - November Dances Part 2 of 3, 2007 November 17; 27
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0035)
  - November Dances Part 1 of 3, 2007 November 17; 28
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0034)
  - November Dances Dress Rehearsal Part 2, 2007 November 16; 29
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0033)
  - November Dances Dress Rehearsal Part 1, 2007 November 16; 30
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0032)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday, Part I, 2007 April 22; 31
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0031)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday, Part II, 2007 April 22; 32
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0030)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Tape 1 of 2, 2007 April 21; 33
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0029)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Tape 1 of 2, 2007 April 21; 34
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0028)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Dress Rehearsal, 2007 April 21; 35
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0027)
  - "Celta" Quinn Lipton Thesis, 2007 April 14; 36
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0026)
  - November Dances Sunday 1 of 2, 2006 November 19; 37
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0025)
  - November Dances Sunday 2 of 2, 2006 November 19; 38
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0024)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday 1 of 2, 2006 April 2; 39
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0023)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday 2 of 2, 2006 April 2; 40
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0022)
  - Ark Dances, 2006; 41
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0021)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday Full, 2005 April 3; 42
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0020)
  - November Dances 2004 1st half, 2004 November 6; 43
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0019)
  - November Dances Sat 2nd & Half Sun 1st half, 2004 November 6-7; 44
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0018)
  - Ark Dances, 2004 April 10; 45
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0017)
  - ChoreoLab, 2004 March 28; 46
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0016)
  - November Dances 2003, 2003 November 22; 47
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0015)
  - Kumudini Lakuia Open Rehearsal, 2003 October 8; 48
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0014)
  - K. Lakhiz Guest Choreo, 2003 October 6; 49
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0013)
  - Ark Dances, 2003 April 12; 50
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0012)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab Tape 1, 2003 March 30; 51
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0011)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab Tape 2, 2003 March 30; 52
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0010)
  - Remembering a Wedding, 2002 November 3; 53
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0009)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 2 Tape 1, 2002 November; 54
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0008)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 2 Tape 2, 2002 November; 55
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0007)
  - Ark Dances 2002 #1, 2002 April 12; 56
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0006)
  - Ark Dances 2002 #2, 2002 April 12; 57
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0005)
  - ChoreoLab 2002 Pt 2 (wide), 58
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0004)
  - ChoreoLab 2002 Pt 1 (wide), 59
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0003)
  - December Dances 2001, 2001 December 1; 60
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0002)
  - December Dances 2001 (#2), 2001 December 1; 61
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette Mini DV_0001)
- Video Cassettes, 1990-2005; 3
  - November Dances, 2005 November 20; 62
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0053)
  - November Dances, 2005 November 19; 63
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0052)
  - ChoreoLab 2005, 2005 April 3; 64
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0051)
  - Choreolab 2005, 2005 April 2; 65
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0050)
  - November Dances 2004, 2004 November 6; 66
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0049)
  - November Dances 2004, 2004 November 7; 67
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0048)
  - Composition Showing, 2004 April 19; 68
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0047)
  - Ark Dances, 2004 April 10; 69
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0046)
  - ChoreoLab 2004, 2004 March 28; 70
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0045)
  - November Dances 2003, 2003 November 22; 71
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0054)
  - Ark Dances 2003, 2003 April 12; 72
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0044)
  - ChoreoLab 2003, 2003 March 30; 73
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0043)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 1 Tape 1, 2002 November; 74
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0042)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 1 Tape 2, 2002 November; 75
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0041)
  - Ark Dances, 2002 April 13; 76
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0040)
  - ChoreoLab 2002, 2002 March 29-31; 77
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0039)
  - December Dances 2001, 2001 December 1; 78
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0038)
  - ChoreoLab 2001, 79
    - Original videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette VHS_0037)
  - December Dances 2000, 2000 December; 80
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0055)
  - ChoreoLab 2000, 2000 April 7-8; 81
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0036)
  - December Dances 1999, 1999 December 4; 82
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0035)
  - Ark Dances, 1999 April; 83
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0034)
  - December Dances 1998, 1998 December 4; 84
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0033)
  - Ark Dances, 1998 April 17; 85
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0032)
  - Reading, Writing, Representin' Conference Roundtable, 1998 April 11; 86
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0031)
  - Reading, Writing, Representin' Conference Performance, 1998 April 11; 87
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0030)
  - December Dances, 1997 December 6; 88
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0029)
  - NC Dance Festival Triangle Night, 1997 September 25; 89
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0028)
  - Ark Dances, 1997 Spring; 90
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0027)
  - December Dances, 1996 December 7; 91
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0026)
  - Senior Dance Concert, 1996 Spring; 92
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0025)
  - Ark Dances, 1996 April 12; 93
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0024)
  - December Dances, 1995 December 1; 94
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0023)
  - Composition Class Final, 1995 April 26; 95
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0022)
  - Ark Dances, 1995 April 8; 96
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0021)
  - Four Ballets, 1995 March 31; 97
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0020)
  - Composition Class Final, 1994 December 7; 98
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0019)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1994 December 3; 99
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0018)
  - Ark Dances, 1994 Fall; 100
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0017)
  - Clay Taliaferro and Friends, 1994 March 18; 101
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0016)
  - Composition Class Final, 1993 December 8; 102
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0015)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1993 December 3; 103
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0014)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1992 December 3-5; 104
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0013)
  - Ark Dances, 1993 November 12; 105
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0012)
  - Comp Class, 1992 April 30; 106
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0011)
  - Ark Dances, 1992 April 17; 107
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0010)
  - Duke Dance Concert, 1992 April 3; 108
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0009)
  - Duke Dance Concert, 1991 September 27-28; 109
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0008)
  - Duke Faculty at UNCG, 1991 September 11; 110
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0007)
  - Ark Dances, 1991 April 11-12; 111
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0006)
  - Lorca Dances, 1991 April 5-6; 112
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0005)
  - Julia Wray Dance, 1990 December 1; 113
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0004)
  - Ark Dances, 1990 November 17; 114
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0003)
  - Dance and Drumming, 1990 September 14; 115
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0002)
  - Ark Dances, 1990 April 14; 116
    - Original videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette VHS_0001)